Ever feel
claustrophobic in
a busy parking lot?
worried you might hit a car while pulling in?
Well, worry no more.
Allow us to present to you
our autonomous
parking system
for one-tenth scale cars.
With automated
parking,
you can relax the
knowledge that
your car will not
be the cause of
any accident
while parking.
But how exactly does it
work, you might ask?
When the vehicle's
ready to park,
the parking system is run.
This ZED stereo
camera captures
a point cloud data of
the area
surrounding the front
of the vehicle.
This data is then
filtered by points
along the ground
plane of the ground,
the color of the
parking space,
and the distance
between the lines
all in order to get
the center point of
the parking spot and the
slopes from the
parking spot.
This center point of
the parking spot and
the center point of
vehicle is then used
alongside two
tangent control
points that chart a
cubic bezier curve between
the points in order to
have the car smoothly
pull in.
So this is the original point cloud
.
that the camera is seeing.
This is it filtered by the plane.
.
And then this is it filtered
for the colour green.
.
And these are the lines
superimposed on top of the parking spot.
.
And then these are the locations
of the various centroids of the line.
.
So you can see that there is a line here,
there is a line here,
.
and there is a line here.
And from the two centroids
.
that we had here and here,
you can get a parking spot location at
.
the middle of the two centroids.
The control system works
using a form of pure
pursuit control.
The system starts
off by turning
the path into a set of
points for the
car to follow.
The system then calculates
the angle between
the current path
and the path that
must be followed to
reach the next point.
The car then steers to follow
the path until it
is close enough to
the next point.
This process
continues until
the car is parked.
Our system also has
an obstacle avoidance
mechanism for,
say, a jaywalking pedestrian.
First, the
perception system
filters away
everything on
the ground so you can
separate the obstacles
from the parking lots,
then the car waits
until the obstacle
moves out of the way.
I said... move
out of the way!
Better.
Now, we return to the control
system and the car parks.
Wow. Let's see a demo of
this concept in
motion.